Emerson, Harrington Files 5166
Kheel Center for Labor-Management Documentation & Archives
- Documents - S, 1905-1923 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  (to) Safeguard the Seas 24 p., Santa Fe System, Rules & Instructions for Belt Repairmen 14 p., Saving 6 p., Scientific Selection of Employees and Its Bearing on Industrial Efficiency 6 p., Securing Efficiency In Railroad Work 38 p., Service Versus Profits 16 p., Shop Betterment and the Individual Effort Method of Profit Sharing 12 p., Short Cuts 24 p., Society of Industrial Engineers 18 p., Some Experience of An Efficiency Engineer 19 p., Some Interesting Experiences of An Efficiency Engineer 9p., S (cont), Sound Economics Can Cure Industrial Obsessions 6 p., (the) Steam Locomotive More Economical Than Electric Equipment for Standard Railroad Operation 5 p., Study of the Fundamentals of Industrial Accounting As Applied to Railroads and Also a Study of the Fundamentals of Good Operation 15 p., Submarines and Coal, How Fuel Famine in New York Was Produced by Germany 3 p., Substitution of the Electric Motor for the Steam Locomotive 3 p., Suggestions for An Executive 5 p., Synopsis of Four Lectures on the Philosophy of Efficiency 4 p.
- Documents - S (Box 2, Folder 23)
- Documents - R, 1916-1924 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  Railroad Eight Hour Law - How to Get Good Out of Evil 4 p., Railroad Perpetuation and Operation 3 p., Railroad Piece Rates 8 p., (The) Railroad Situation 47 p. 22, (The) Railroad Situation 16 p., The Rate Decision 4 p., Rational Basis for Wages 11 p., Reading of Character and Aptitudes 11 p., Rehabilitation of Silver As part of the Money Basis of the World 8 p., Resolved: That Workers Should Participate In the Management 6 p., Resume of the Work of the Emerson Company On the Baltimore and Ohio Railroad 20 p., Revision of American Foundrymen's Association Standard Cost System 21 p., Rewards of Efficiency 31 p., Rising Wages 12 p.
- Documents - R, 1916-1924 (Box 2, Folder 21)
- Documents - P, 1908-1931 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  Philosophy of Efficiency - A Synopsis of Four Lectures 3 p., Philosophy of Efficiency, An Outline of Its Elements. 9 p., Philosophy of Work 7 p., Practicing Efficiency and Knowing Costs 12 p., Present Day Inefficiency, Its Cause and the Remedy 19 p., Preserving of Ties 12 p., Preventable Wastes and Losses on Railroads 15 p., Principles First, Then Details 5 p., Principles of Efficiency Applied to Water Works 8 p., Principles On Which Industrial Leadership Rests 7 p., Principles Underlying Office Management 32 p., Principles Underlying Scientific Management 17 p., (The) Problem - The Old Industrial Age And the New 31 p., Program of Harrington Emerson for a Great Railroad 3 p., Project for a Company to Become Very Profitable and Very Large
- Documents - P, 1908-1931 (Box 2, Folder 19)
- Documents - W, 1918-1922 (Box 2, Folder 27)
  Wage-Payment Plans - A Discussion 4 p., Wastes In American Transportation 54 p, Western Allies, The Hear and the Far East In the World War, Worthy and Unworthy Alliances 11 p., What Is Ahead of Us 4 p., Who Has the Right to Strike 11 p., Why Should the Spirit of Mortal Be Proud 16 p., World Peace 27p.
- Lesson 1 - Course of Human Engineering (Box 3, Folder 19)
  23 p
- Lesson 13 - Planning (Box 3, Folder 31)
  18 p
- Lesson 12 - The Value of Records (Box 3, Folder 30)
  13 p
- Lesson 11 - Introduction of the Thirteen Principles of Efficiency (Box 3, Folder 29)
  10 pg
- Lesson 10 - Three Kinds of Producers - Materials for Maintenance and for Manufacture (Box 3, Folder 28)
- Lesson 9 - Three Kinds of Producers - The Machine Consisting of Money, Stores, Equipment, Investment (Box 3, Folder 27)
  15 p
- Lesson 8 - Three Kinds of Producers - Men - Supervisors and Workers! (Box 3, Folder 26)
  14 p
- Lesson 7 - Self-Organization - Practical Methods (Box 3, Folder 25)
  16 p
- Lesson 6 - The Mechanics of Self-Improvement (Box 3, Folder 24)
- Lesson 5 - Education and Industrial Competence (Box 3, Folder 23)
  20 p
- Lesson 4 - The Seven Moralities (Box 3, Folder 22)
  22 p
- Lesson 13 - The Fair Deal (Box 3, Folder 7)
  27 p
- Lesson 2 - Fitting a Job to Yourself (Box 3, Folder 20)
- Lesson 17 - Standardized Operations (Box 3, Folder 34)
- Lesson 24 - How to Use the Principles (Box 3, Folder 18)
- Lesson 23 - Organization, Administration, Management and Operation (Box 3, Folder 17)
- Lesson 22 - Efficient Salesmanship (Box 3, Folder 16)
- Lesson 21 - Efficient Self -Education (Box 3, Folder 15)
  21 p
- Lesson 20 - Finances (Box 3, Folder 14)
- Lesson 19 - Amenities (Box 3, Folder 13)
- Lesson 18 - Efficient Home Management (Box 3, Folder 12)
  37 p
- Lesson 17 - Efficient Memory (Box 3, Folder 11)
- Lesson 16 - Health Culture - Part Two (Box 3, Folder 10)
  24 p
- Lesson 15 - Health Culture - Part One (Box 3, Folder 9)
  29 p
- Lesson 14 - Efficiency Reward (Box 3, Folder 8)
  19 p
- Lesson 3 - Classifying Yourself (Box 3, Folder 21)
- Company Documents, 1917-1919 (Box 3, Folder 45)
  Includes 8 p. memo, "to the members of the Emerson Company," "Preamble" of the aims and organization 47 p., "to the members and groups constituting the NY Agency of the Emerson Co." 8 p., "What is the Emerson Company and Who Are Its Employes And Associates?" 16 p., "The Director's Division of the Emerson Engineers" 25 p., "the Records and Reports of the Emerson Engineers" 25 p. to Associates, "Standard Practice Instructions"
- Lesson 11 - Competent Counsel (Box 3, Folder 5)
- Lesson 10 - Common Sense (Box 3, Folder 4)
  25 p
- Lesson 9 - Ideals (Box 3, Folder 3)
- Lesson 8 - Written Standard Practice Instructions (Box 3, Folder 2)
- Lesson 7 - Standardized Operations (Box 3, Folder 1)
- Staff Bulletin (Box 3, Folder 53)
  publication of Emerson Engineers for staff
- Financial and Tax Data, 1950-1959 (Box 3, Folder 52)
- Agreements, 1959-1962 (Box 3, Folder 51)
- "A Selection of Articles and Press Comments," Emerson Consultants, 1963 (Box 3, Folder 50)
- Company Documents (Box 3, Folder 49)
  Includes printed company documents concerning all aspects of company activities & descriptions of services offered by Emerson Co.
- An Outline of the Working Plan for the Emerson Engineers Accompanied With Illustrations of Various Features of the Plan (Box 3, Folder 48)
- Lesson 14 - Schedules (Box 3, Folder 32)
- Company Documents (Box 3, Folder 46)
  "Division of Our Service" 6 p., "Standard Letters and Paragraphs for Use in Writing Prospects," "to the Emerson Company Workers - Staff and Line" 7 p., "the Old Home and the New of the Emerson Engineers" 9 p., and also bonus plan, & misc. related company documents.
- Lesson 16 - Standardized Conditions (Box 3, Folder 33)
  12 pg
- Lesson 1-12 - "Emerson Institute of Efficiency" (Box 3, Folder 44)
  Undated leaflets (lessons) - A Home Course In Personal Efficiency
- Lesson 26 - How to Use the Principles (Box 3, Folder 43)
- Lesson 25 - Amenities (Box 3, Folder 42)
- Lesson 24 - Efficiency Reward (Box 3, Folder 41)
- Lesson 23 - (Answer booklet only) (Box 3, Folder 40)
- Lesson 22 - Discipline (Box 3, Folder 39)
- Lesson 21 - Competent Counsel (Box 3, Folder 38)
- Lesson 20 - Common Sense (Box 3, Folder 37)
- Lesson 19 - Ideals (Box 3, Folder 36)
- Lesson 18 - Written Standard Practice Instructions (Box 3, Folder 35)
- Lesson 12 - Discipline (Box 3, Folder 6)
- Company Documents (Box 3, Folder 47)
- American Management Association, Measuring and Grading the Supervisory Forces, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Baltimore and Ohio Railroad, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 1)
- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 24)
  Includes reports, investigations and studies of various railroad companies as well as general railroad reports
- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 25)
- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 26)
- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 27)
- Wastes in Industry (Box 4, Folder 28)
  Includes reports on wastes in American transportation, report on prevention of industrial wastes (Emerson member of Hoover Committee)
- Aaron, Charles F, From Pasture to Pulley, 1907 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  80 pg
- American Engineer and Railroad Journal, Betterment Work on the Santa Fe, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  28 pg
- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 22)
- American Management Association, Essential Personnel Record, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  43 pg
- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 21)
- American Railroad Association Code of Rules, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  58 pg
- American Society of Mechanical Engineers, Jt. Committee on Standards for Graphic Presentation, Preliminary Report (Box 4, Folder 29)
  8 pg
- Association of Consulting Management Engineers, The Profession of Management, 1937 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  29 pg
- Atkinson, Guy, Failures, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  14 pg
- Atkinson, Guy, Some Domestic Limitations to Foreign Trade After the War, 1918 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Baltimore and Ohio Railroad Company Annual Report, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  48 pg
- Bateman, J.M., How a Large Manufacturing Company Disposes of Its Old Metal, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Benge, Eugene J., Graphic Control In Labor Budgeting, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  16 pg
- American Foundrymen's Association, Annual Reports, Constitution, 1913-1915 (Box 4, Folder 29)
- Curtis Publishing Co., 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 12)
- Chicago, Rock Island and Pacific Railroad, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 2)
- Curtis Publishing Co., 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 3)
- Curtis Publishing Co., 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 4)
- Curtis Publishing Co., 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 5)
- Curtis Publishing Co., 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 6)
- Curtis Publishing Co., 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 7)
- Curtis Publishing Co., 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 8)
- Curtis Publishing Co., 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 9)
- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 23)
- Curtis Publishing Co., 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 11)
- Blackford, Katharine, Scientific Selecting and Assignment of Men in the Creation of An Organization, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Curtis Publishing Co., 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 13)
- Curtis Publishing Co., 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 14)
- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 15)
- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 16)
- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 17)
- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 18)
- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 19)
- Railroads (Box 4, Folder 20)
- Curtis Publishing Co., 1909-1911 (Box 4, Folder 10)
- Friedensburg, Ferdinand, The Practical Results of Workingmen's Insurance in Germany, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  62 pg
- Dickerman, W. C., Incentives for Individual Protection, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Dietz, Carl F., The Selection of Grinding Wheels for the Foundry (Box 4, Folder 32)
  22 pg
- Draper, Ernest, How Some Manufacturers Have Met Seasonal Unemployment, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 32)
- Drier, Thomas, Harrington Emerson and Efficiency, 1911 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  3 pg
- Educational Exhibition Co. Materials for the Graphic Presentation of Facts, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  20 pg
- Efficiency Society Journal, 1915-1917 (Box 4, Folder 33)
- Falconer Company - Pulling Power, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  15 pg
- Farnham, Dwight T., Efficient Management for the Factory of Moderate Size, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Blackford, Katherine, Efficiency In the Manufacture of Railway Transportation, 1913 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  5 pg
- Freyd, Max, An Appraisal of Relative Merits of Types of Rating Scales & Their Use, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Cotton Manufactures Association of North Carolina, Proceedings of the 11th Annual Convention, 1917 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  110 pg
- Fry, Charles H, Betterment Work on the Santa Fe, 1906 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  32 pg
- Garvey, John A., Rating In Theory and Practice, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Grassmuck, Chester, Payroll Budgeting, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Gregg, A. W., Notes on Safety Organization (Box 4, Folder 35)
- Gregson, John, Canister Lining in Side Blow Converters (Box 4, Folder 35)
  6 pg
- Hall, John H., Defects in Steel Castings and the Remedies for Them (Box 4, Folder 36)
  39 pg
- Hemenway, Harold, Calculating Mixtures for Mallable Cast Iron (Box 4, Folder 36)
  26 pg
- Hoit, Rose & Troster, Manual of Chair Store Companies, 1927 (Box 4, Folder 36)
- Flying, Vol. IX. No. 11, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 34)
- Chamber of Commerce of the U.S. Chamber of Commerce of the U.S. Collection of Business Figures (Box 4, Folder 31)
  42 pg
- Howell, Alfred E., One Third of a Century in a Gray Iron Foundry (Box 4, Folder 36)
- The Scientific Selection and Management of Employees (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Blackwood, A. F. Stirling, General Melting Characteristics of Acid Steel for Castings (Box 4, Folder 30)
  31 pg
- Bloedel Donovan Lumber Mills, Shop Committee Plans and Standard Practice Rules, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Bradley, Albert, Setting Up A Forecasting Program, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Brinkman, E.E., Extra Financial Incentives For Supervisors, 1926 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Bureau of Railway Economics, Railway Revenues and Expenses, 1920 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  4 pg
- Caesar, G.V., The Annealing Properties of Copper, 1916 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Dallas, C. Donald, The Spirit of Paul Revere - A Glorious Heritage for American Industry, 1944 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  52 pg
- Casson, Herbert, The Story of Emerson, High Priest of the New Science of Efficiency (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Dallas, C. Donald, The Price of Overconfidence (Box 4, Folder 32)
  44 pg
- Cooperative Industrial Research (Box 4, Folder 31)
  38 pg
- Cost Accounting Through the Use of Standards, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Foremanship, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  47 pg
- Uniform Cost Accounting in Trade Association's, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Chicago, Great Western Railroad. Regulations, 1915 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Book of Rules, 1919 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  168 pg
- Cliffe, Frank B., Budgeting Practices and Experiences of the General Electric Company, 1925 (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Cornaro, Luigi, The Art of Living Long (Box 4, Folder 31)
  23 pg
- Employers' Manual, 1912 (Box 4, Folder 30)
- Carlson, W. W., Suggested Standard for Pattern Parts (Box 4, Folder 31)
- Murphey, James A., The Use of Borings in Cupola Operations (Box 5, Folder 5)
  7 pg
- Interborough Rapid Transit Company, Annual Report, 1919-1920 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Metcalf, Henry C., Some Major Aspects of Employee Representation, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Metropolitan Life Insurance Company, The Job Blueprint, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  11 pg
- Studying Business (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Moldenke, Richard, Memorandum on the Preparation of Standard Specifications for Cast Iron for International Export Use, 1915 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Molding Sand Tests (Box 5, Folder 5)
  18 pg
- Morel, F., Safety and Sanitation in the Brass Foundry (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Morey, Arthur T., Progress in the Safety Movement and the Latest Aids to Good Safety Work (Box 5, Folder 5)
- McKinney, P. E., Aluminum Castings and Forgings, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Mulvey, James, Green Sand Cores (Box 5, Folder 5)
- McCormick, Cyrus, Employee Representation As Affecting the Attitude of Labor and Business, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Nash, Arthur, The Golden Rule in Business, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- New York Stock Exchange and Affiliated Companies Retirement Plans, 1925 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Newton, Richard C., How Can A Man Keep Well and Grow Old? (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Nisbet, W. C., Standard Time and Bonus Applied to Track Labor, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 6)
  40 pg
- Northam, M.P., Do You Ever Think About These Things? (Box 5, Folder 6)
- How to Get Ahead, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- How We Can Help One Another, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 6)
- Pace Student, Vol. II, No. 3, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  February, includes editorial about H.E.
- Morgan, Earl B., Budgeting Man Power, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Kellogg, R.S., The Cost of Growing Timber, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- The Greatest Railway on Earth, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Speaking of Subways, 1921 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- Your Subways, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 1)
- International Railway Fuel Association, Fourteenth Annual Meeting, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 1)
  194 pg
- Jacobs, H. W., Organization and Economy in the Railway Machine Shop, 1907 (Box 5, Folder 2)
  72 pg
- Jappe, K.W., The Need for Bread and Butter Economics (Box 5, Folder 2)
  30 pg
- Tariff Bargaining, 1934 (Box 5, Folder 2)
- Trends in Business and Commodity Prices (Box 5, Folder 2)
- McKinsey, J. O., Sixteen Trends In Management Organization, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 5)
  24 pg
- Kelley, Walter H., Refractories - Their Selection and Use in the Foundry (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Mexico - General Descriptive Data, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Kreuzpointer, Paul, Report of Committee on Industrial Education (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Report on Fifth Annual Conservation Congress, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 3)
- LaSalle Extension University, Educating for Management, 1933 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Lewisohn, Sam A., A National Management Clearing House, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Libby, S. H., Selection of Electric Motors and Controllers in the Foundry (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Lindsay, Forbes, Efficiency, 1917 (Box 5, Folder 4)
  Pacific Mutual School for Salesmen, Sect 1 - Mental Efficiency (Lessons 2, 3 & 4)
- Lytle, C. W., Management Engineering Summary Sheet, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 4)
- Maujer, A.R., Editorials RE: H. Emerson, 1923-1953 (Box 5, Folder 5)
- Keep, W. J., Coke Recovered From the Cupola Dump (Box 5, Folder 3)
- Wallace, R. S. B., The Making of Thin-Walled Castings, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 13)
- A System of Accounts for Retail Merchants, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  19 pg
- U.S. Government Printing Office, Foreign Relations of the U.S., 1919 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  50 pg
- Publications of the Interstate Commerce Commission, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Standards of Weight & Measure, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  35 pg
- Transportation, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- U. S. War Industries Board, Prices of Fibers and Fiber Products, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- United States Steel Corporation, The Story of Steel, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  63 pg
- University of the State of New York Bulletin, Professional Engineers and Land Surveyors, 1938 (Box 5, Folder 11)
  280 pg
- Palmer, Virgil M., Determination of Base Roles for Manual Workers, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Van Alstyne, David, Profitable Ethics, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 12)
  13 pg
- Touceda, Enrique, Remarks on the Strength and Ductility of Malleable Cast Iron After the Skin Has Been Removed (Box 5, Folder 10)
- West, Ralph, Theory and Practice in Gating and Heading Steel Castings (Box 5, Folder 13)
- West, Thomas D., Evils Embodied in Specialization (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Williams, R. G., Safety in Connection With Grinding Wheels (Box 5, Folder 13)
- Zimmerschied, K. W., A Cast Iron With Unusual Structure (Box 5, Folder 14)
- Newspaper clippings, 1910-1921 (Box 5, Folder 15)
- Newspaper clippings, 1910-1921 (Box 5, Folder 16)
- Newspaper clippings, 1910-1921 (Box 5, Folder 17)
- Speech of Herbert Hoover and other misc, 1919 (Box 5, Folder 18)
  Sept. 16th
- Urwick, L., The Pioneers of Scientific Management (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Rowley, A. W., Salary vs. Extra Financial Incentive Methods of Compensating Supervisors, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Harrington Emerson's letters of Associates -Ramblings (Box 5, Folder 19)
  Handwritten index cards
- Parlette, Ralph, It's Up to You!, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Pittsburgh and Lake Erie Railroad Company, Annual Report, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Platt & Washburn Refining Co. Veedol - Lubrication of Internal Combustion Motors, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 7)
  87 pg
- Pollard, A.L., Effect of Varying Silicon and Carbon in Malleable Iron Mixtures (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Reidenbach, F. W., Safety First (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Reitinger, Harry, Sound Wage Incentives (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Remerrah, Einstein's Theory of Relativity (Box 5, Folder 8)
- U. S. Federal Trade Commission, Fundamentals of a Cost System for Manufacturers, 1916 (Box 5, Folder 11)
- Roberts, W. H., The Principles of Efficiency, 1911 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- Tyler, Leonard, Forecasting the Manufacturing Program, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- The Sabean, Vol. 7, No. 3, 1922 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  March
- Sethi, Narendra, Harrington Emerson - A Pioneer in Management Movement, 1968 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Shepard, George H, The Principles of Efficiency, Applied, 1913 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Stevens, C. E., Foremen's Meetings On Efficiency of Operation, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 9)
- Storey, Oliver W., Researches in the Annealing Process for Malleable Castings (Box 5, Folder 9)
  17 pg
- Symons, Wilson E., The Practical Application of Scientific Management to Railway Operations, 1912 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  159 pg
- Szepesi, Eugene, Efficiency in the Textile Industry, 1920 (Box 5, Folder 9)
  9 pg
- Taylor, Frederick W., Shop Management, 1903 (Box 5, Folder 10)
- Pan American Union, Mexico, The City of Palaces, 1918 (Box 5, Folder 7)
- Roberts, John, Canadian National Railways Co-operative Plan, 1926 (Box 5, Folder 8)
- American Thompson Improved Indicator (Box 6, Folder 3)
  Records the pressure and rate of pressure change in the cylinders of steam engines.
- Bristol Electric Pyrometer (Box 6, Folder 2)
  Model 133: no.97
- Monroe High Speed Electric Adding Machine (Box 6, Folder 1)
  Electric with rotted cord: does not work.
- Workingman's Advocate (Nat'l. Reform Assn.), Nov. 2, 1844 (Box 7)
- Images digitized from the collection. (Box 8)